Finding Aid for Aldred Scott Warthin pamphlets and reprints, 1909-1929
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Aldred Scott Warthin pamphlets and reprints 1909-1929
Warthin, Aldred Scott, 1866-1931.
1 box
[747] DA 2; W297; P186
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The provenance of these material is unknown.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Aldred Scott Warthin was a pathologist and professor of pathology at the University of Michigan.
This collection of Aldred Scott Warthin pamphlets and reprints was accumulated from different sources. It has been arranged alphabetically by title.
- Pamphlets and reprints
  - Application of the Warthin-Starry silver agar method, 1923 (Box 1)
  - A biologic philosophy or religion a necessary foundation for race betterment, undated (Box 1)
  - Cactus-spine pseudotubercles, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Cardiovascular syphilis, 1927 (Box 1)
  - The constitutional entity of exopthalmic goiter and so-called toxic adenoma, 1928 (Box 1)
  - The differential diagnosis of chancre and carcinoma of the cervix, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The effect of roentgen rays on the heart: I. The microscopic changes in the heart muscle of rats and rabbits following a single exposure, 1927 (Box 1)
  - The effect of roentgen rays on the heart: II. The microscopic changes in the heart muscle of rats and rabbits following a series of exposures, 1929 (Box 1)
  - The excretion of spirochaeta pallida. through the kidneys, 1922 (Box 1)
  - An experimental investigation as to the possible etiologic relationship of monilia psilosis to pernicious anemia, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Hyperthropy of the hemolymph nodes in Texas-fever imaunes, 1923 (Box 1)
  - Increasing human incidence of broad tapeworm infestation in Great Lakes region, 1928 (Box 1)
  - John George Adami: an appreciation, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Lesions of latent syphilis, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Marcello Malpighi, 1628-1694, 1929 (Box 1)
  - The medical library of the University of Michigan, 1917 (Box 1)
  - Medical observations in Hawaii, 1928 (Box 1)
  - The molasses plate method for the staining of many paraffin sections at one time, 1924 (Box 1)
  - The myocardial lesions of diphtheria, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Noah Webster as epidemiologist, 1923 (Box 1)
  - The occurrence of entamoeba histolytica with tissue lesions in the testis and epididymis in chronic dysentery, 1922 (Box 1)
  - The occurrence of hepatic lesions in patients treated by intensive deep roentgen irradiation, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Osler and the International Association of Medical Museums, 1927 (Box 1)
  - The pathology of the aging process, 1928 (Box 1)
  - The pathology of the skin lesions produced by mustard gas (dichlorethylsulphide), 1918 (Box 1)
  - The physical health of the University, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Pigmentation of the skin (Addison's disease) associated with lymphosarcoma, 1924 (Box 1)
  - A preliminary report on the cerebral pathology of human botulism resulting from canned spinach, 1922 (Box 1)
  - President's address: The nature of cancer susceptibility in human families, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Recreations for physicians, 1926 (Box 1)
  - The relation of cancer of the stomach to ulcers, 1927 (Box 1)
  - The relation of diet to pernicious anemia, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Sex differences in the pathologic picture of syphilis, 1928 (Box 1)
  - The significance of the association in American medicine, 1928 (Box 1)
  - A silver-starch-gelatin method for demonstration of spirochetes in single tissue sections, 1929 (Box 1)
  - The staining of spirochetes in cover-glass smears by the silver-agar method, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Syphilis of the medium and smaller arteries, 1922 (Box 1)
  - The teaching of physical therapy, 1927 (Box 1)
  - The university medical school and the state, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Virchow's conception of constitutional syphilis, 1926 (Box 1)